[music]
[Instructor] Cool so we've added
our sounds for Jumping and Crashing,
which is great.
Now, we're going to go back
into our PlayerController Script,
and we're just going to create
another...private variable
for our Component,
so this one'll be,
in this case we want Audio, right,
we want to be able to emit
the Audio from our Player,
so the Player needs
an "Audio Source".
We take the "AudioSource"
of our Player,
and we'll just call this
"playerAudio."
So, this is the Audio
that plays from the Player,
and our Start() method,
we're very familiar now,
so we'll use our playerAudio variable,
and we're going to set it...
to our...
"Audio Source" Component,
so, "GetComponent()"
So now, since we have our jump,
and our crash sound
what we need to do is actually
play those Audio clips.
So, down in our code,
when the Player jumps,
we're actually going to use
our new playerAudio variable,
and we're going to use a new method,
and so there's specifically
one called "Play()".
There's a "playOnAwake",
so when anything starts, it'll play.
And then there's a "PlayOneShot(),"
so basically that'll just play it once,
and then we'll be done.
So we PlayOneShot(),
and then we want our AudioClip,
so this our jump, so our "jumpSound,"
and then it looks like
there's another variable
that we can add, so we can
actually change the Volume
when we play our jump sound.
We'll just set it to be,
we'll just leave
it to the full Volume for now.
And then, we're going to do
the same thing
for when the game is over,
so we're going
to use our playerAudio,
and we're going to PlayOneShot(),
because we actually need
to use AudioClips in this,
and then, in this case,
we're going to use our "crashSound,"
and we're going to set it to...
full Volume,
once again.
Cool. Now we save, so when
we go back into Unity,
now, when we play our game,
we should hear some Effects
when we jump, and when we crash.
[happy game music]
And we jump.
And I didn't hear anything.
What if we crash,
what's going to happen?
It didn't seem like
anything happened?
Let's see, let's go,
let's look at our errors.
There's no Audio Source oh!
I made a mistake.
So, in Player, we actually
need to add the Audio Source,
because we didn't actually
use one.
Let's go add a Component,
we're going to look
for an Audio Source,
there you go.
So now that we have the Audio Source
that we're using,
and we have the clips
that the Audio Source
will be playing,
now when we press Play,
that error should go away,
[happy game music] and we jump.
[jump sound]
There you go and then,
I can't stop jumping right now,
it's just too exciting,
and then when I crash finally,
[crash noise] Nice!
Awesome, so
now we have an amazing game...
full of Sound Effects and Audio,
so what you're going to do is
you're going to make sure
that you add an Audio Source
to your Player.
Don't make that mistake like I did,
and then in your
PlayerController class,
you're going to get an AudioSource
variable and we'll just call it the
playerAudio, so that way, we can emit
any of the clips that play,
so that way,
our Camera can hear it.
In our Start() method, make sure
that you get the Component
for our playerAudio,
which will be
our AudioSource that we added.
In our Update() method,
make sure
that whenever the Player
presses the space bar,
you make sure to PlayOneShot(),
so then that way
the OneShot will actually play
the AudioClips that we have saved.
We'll play the jumpSound,
and we'll make sure
that it's at full Volume.
And then in our OnCollisionEnter(),
when we Collide with an Obstacle,
we're going to do another OneShot
and we're going to play our crashSound
at full Volume.
So, now it's your turn.
[music]